Muste, A. J. Papers on Microfilm 5975 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence (1958-1963) (Reel 6)
  - Roszak, Theodore, 19 (Reel 20)
  - Roy, Ralph Lord, 20 (Reel 20)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 21 (Reel 20)
  - S (General), 22 (Reel 20)
  - Sahara Protest Team, 23 (Reel 20)
  - Salstrom, Paul, 24 (Reel 20)
  - SANE, 25 (Reel 20)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 26 (Reel 20)
  - School of Conflict Resolution, 27 (Reel 20)
  - Schutz, Robert, 28 (Reel 20)
  - Scott, Lawrence, 29 (Reel 20)
  - Signatures (A.J. Muste), 30 (Reel 20)
  - Smith Act cases (Denver, CO), 31 (Reel 20)
  - Sobell, Morton, 32 (Reel 20)
  - Sociedades Hispana Confederadas, 33 (Reel 20)
  - Society for Social Responsibility in Science, 34 (Reel 20)
  - South (nonviolent struggle, including sit-ins), 35 (Reel 20)
  - South Africa, 36 (Reel 20)
  - South Africa Action, 37 (Reel 20)
  - Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 38 (Reel 20)
  - Southern Farmer, Inc., 39 (Reel 20)
  - Soviet physicists, 40 (Reel 20)
  - Span, 41 (Reel 20)
  - Steere, Douglas, 42 (Reel 20)
  - Stein, Walter, 43 (Reel 20)
  - Stevens, Henry Bailey, 44 (Reel 20)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1 (Reel 21)
  - Student Peace Union (SPU), 2 (Reel 21)
  - Student Peace Union, New York, 3 (Reel 21)
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 4 (Reel 21)
  - Summit meeting, 5 (Reel 21)
  - Survival, 6 (Reel 21)
  - Swomley, John M., 7 (Reel 21)
  - T (General), 8 (Reel 21)
  - Teachers College Record, 9 (Reel 21)
  - Techniques Conference on Nonviolence, 10 (Reel 21)
  - Testing suit, anti-, 11 (Reel 21)
  - Toll the Bells Committee, 12 (Reel 21)
  - Tucson Protest, 13 (Reel 21)
  - Turn Toward Peace, 14 (Reel 21)
  - Box 39 - U (General), 15 (Reel 21)
  - Union Square May Day Committee, 16 (Reel 21)
  - United Presbyterian Church, 17 (Reel 21)
  - Uphaus appeal, 18 (Reel 21)
  - V (General), 19 (Reel 21)
  - Vedanta movement, 20 (Reel 21)
  - Villar, Melita del, 21 (Reel 21)
  - Volunteer Civil Righs Commission (Carl Braden), 22 (Reel 21)
  - W (General), 23 (Reel 21)
  - Wakefield, Dan (Revolt in the South) correspondence with Grove Press, 24 (Reel 21)
  - Walk for Disarmament, 25 (Reel 21)
  - Walk to Washington, 1963, 26 (Reel 21)
  - Walter, E.V., 27 (Reel 21)
  - War Resisters League World Peace Brigade Conference, 28 (Reel 21)
  - West Side Peace Center, 29 (Reel 21)
  - Wilkerson, Doxey, 1 (Reel 22)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 2 (Reel 22)
  - Women Strike for Peace, 3 (Reel 22)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 4 (Reel 22)
  - World Committee on Peaceful Cooperation, 5 (Reel 22)
  - World Conference on Nonviolence, 6 (Reel 22)
  - World Constitution Convention, 7 (Reel 22)
  - World Council of Churches, 8 (Reel 22)
  - World Council of Peace, 9 (Reel 22)
  - World Fast for Peace, 10 (Reel 22)
  - World Fast for Peace, 11 (Reel 22)
  - World Peace Brigade, 12 (Reel 22)
    - Administrative, Executive, Financial, 13 (Reel 22)
      - Founding Convention, Brummana, Lebanon, 1961-1962; 14 (Reel 22)
        December 1961-January 1962
      - Conference, Beirut, 1962; 15 (Reel 22)
        January 1962 statement, financial
      - Council meeting, London, 1962; 16 (Reel 22)
        July 30 to August 2, 1962, minutes, reports
      - Constitution, 17 (Reel 22)
      - Executive proceedings (Executive Committee), 18 (Reel 22)
      - Financial, 19 (Reel 22)
    - Correspondence (General by subject), 20 (Reel 22)
      - Africa, general, financial, Bayard Rustin material, 21 (Reel 22)
      - Africa seminar on industry and politics in South Africa, 22 (Reel 22)
      - Brigadeers, 23 (Reel 22)
      - Correspondence ("important carbon copies"), 24 (Reel 22)
      - General (except India), 25 (Reel 22)
      - India, 26 (Reel 22)
      - Martin, Barnaby, 27 (Reel 22)
      - Members, 28 (Reel 22)
      - Moss, Lynn, and Ed Lazer, 29 (Reel 22)
      - Officers, 30 (Reel 22)
      - Representation, 31 (Reel 22)
      - Tatum, Lyle, 32 (Reel 22)
      - Visit of A.J. Muste and Jim Bristol with Vinoba Bhave, 1962; 33 (Reel 22)
        December 1962.
    - Africa Freedom Action Project, 34 (Reel 22)
      - General Correspondence, 35 (Reel 22)
      - Tanganyika, general and financial, 36 (Reel 22)
    - Delhi-Peking Friendship March, 37 (Reel 22)
      - General, 38 (Reel 22)
      - Correspondence with Chinese government, 39 (Reel 22)
      - Correspondence with marchers, personnel, 40 (Reel 22)
      - Policy and strategy, publicity, response to Deo statement, Vedchhi statement, 1 (Reel 23)
    - Asian Regional Council, 2 (Reel 23)
    - North American Regional Council, 3 (Reel 23)
      - Board of Directors, minutes, reports, etc., 4 (Reel 23)
      - Financial, 5 (Reel 23)
      - Delhi-Peking Friendship March, financial, 6 (Reel 23)
      - General, 7 (Reel 23)
  - World Youth Festival, 8 (Reel 23)
  - Worldview, 9 (Reel 23)
  - Y (General), 10 (Reel 23)
  - Yale-Russian Chorus (Peter Ralph), 11 (Reel 23)
  - Youth Confreence on Nonviolence and Socio-Economic Change, 12 (Reel 23)
  - Youth March for Integration, 13 (Reel 23)
  - Yungblut, John, 14 (Reel 23)
  - Zahn, Franklin, 15 (Reel 23)
- Correspondence (1964-1967), 16 (Reel 23)
  - A (General), 17 (Reel 23)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 18 (Reel 23)
  - Academicians and professors (signers of New York Times ad regarding Vietnam bombing), 19 (Reel 23)
  - Africa, 20 (Reel 23)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 21 (Reel 23)
  - Anti-escalation Committee, 22 (Reel 23)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 23 (Reel 23)
  - Artists, Writers, and Professionals Protest, 24 (Reel 23)
  - B (General), 25 (Reel 23)
  - Black Power, 26 (Reel 23)
  - C (General), 27 (Reel 23)
  - Canada, 28 (Reel 23)
  - Civil rights, 29 (Reel 23)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam (CALCAV), 30 (Reel 23)
  - Committee for Nonviolent Action (CNVA), 1 (Reel 24)
    - Contributions and appeals, 2 (Reel 24)
    - Contributions (finances), 3 (Reel 24)
    - Contributions (lists), 4 (Reel 24)
    - CNVA Correspondence (General), 5 (Reel 24)
    - Finances, 6 (Reel 24)
    - Latin America, 7 (Reel 24)
    - Reports and related correspondence, 8 (Reel 24)
    - Haworth fine, 9 (Reel 24)
    - Saigon project: Minutes (subcommittee on Vietnam Project, 1966), 10 (Reel 24)
    - Preparations, 11 (Reel 24)
    - Fund appeals, 12 (Reel 24)
    - Publicity and reports, 13 (Reel 24)
    - Contacts, 14 (Reel 24)
    - Follow-up, 15 (Reel 24)
    - CNVA, New England, 16 (Reel 24)
    - CNVA, West, 17 (Reel 24)
  - Committee on US-USSR (Peace leadership exchange), 1 (Reel 25)
  - Congress of American Professors, 2 (Reel 25)
  - Conscientious Objection, 3 (Reel 25)
  - D (General), 4 (Reel 25)
  - Directions, 5 (Reel 25)
  - Dissenting GI's, 6 (Reel 25)
  - Dominican Republic, 7 (Reel 25)
  - Draft, 8 (Reel 25)
  - Draft card burning and subpoenas (Union Square, 1965), 9 (Reel 25)
  - E (General), 10 (Reel 25)
  - End the Draft (1967 committee), 11 (Reel 25)
  - F (General), 12 (Reel 25)
  - Ferry, W.H., 13 (Reel 25)
  - Fifth Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade Committee, 14 (Reel 25)
    - Minutes, finances, 15 (Reel 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 16 (Reel 25)
    - Rally, 1965; 17 (Reel 25)
      October 16, 1965.
    - Rally, 1966; 18 (Reel 25)
      March 26, 1966.
    - November 8 Mobilization, 1966; 19 (Reel 25)
      see Mobilization
    - Freedom House Award demonstration, 1966; 1 (Reel 26)
      February 23, 1966.
  - Fort Hood Tree Defense Committee, 2 (Reel 26)
  - Fund appeal contacts, 3 (Reel 26)
  - G (General), 4 (Reel 26)
  - H (General), 5 (Reel 26)
  - Hanoi (miscellaneous), 6 (Reel 26)
  - Hanoi delegation (Lynd-Hayden-Aptheker), 7 (Reel 26)
  - Hanoi Hostage, 8 (Reel 26)
  - Hanoi Hostage (correspondence), 9 (Reel 26)
  - Hanoi Trip, 10 (Reel 26)
    - Correspondence, logistics, and contacts, 11 (Reel 26)
    - Finances, published correspondence, articles, publicity, 12 (Reel 26)
  - Hiroshima Day Observance, 1965; 13 (Reel 26)
    Washington, DC, August 6-9, 1965
  - House Un-American Activities Committee (Pool Bill, HR 12047), 14 (Reel 26)
  - I (General), 15 (Reel 26)
  - India, 16 (Reel 26)
  - Indonesia, 17 (Reel 26)
  - International Confederation for Disarmament and Peace, 18 (Reel 26)
  - J (General), 19 (Reel 26)
  - Japan, 20 (Reel 26)
  - July 4th Demonstration, 1966; 1 (Reel 27)
  - K (General), 2 (Reel 27)
  - Kennan, George, 3 (Reel 27)
  - L (General), 4 (Reel 27)
  - Letters to Editors, 5 (Reel 27)
  - Liberation, 6 (Reel 27)
    material from 1964-1967 has been filed with the main body of correspondence, 1958-1963
  - Lists (important), 7 (Reel 27)
  - M (General), 8 (Reel 27)
  - Mobilization, 9 (Reel 27)
    - National Leadership Conference, Cleveland, Ohio, 1966; 10 (Reel 27)
      September 1966 (Inter-University Committee)
    - Demonstration, 1966; 11 (Reel 27)
      November 8, 1966: Correspondence
    - Releases, reports, Literature, finances, miscellaneous, 12 (Reel 27)
    - Mobilization News, 13 (Reel 27)
    - Cleveland Conference, 1966; 14 (Reel 27)
      November 26, 1966 (toward reconstituted Mobilization Committee)
    - Demonstration, 1967; 1 (Reel 28)
      April 15, 1967.
      - Preceding events, 1967; 2 (Reel 28)
      - Calls, 1967; 3 (Reel 28)
      - Minutes (steering, working, and public relations committees), 1967; 4 (Reel 28)
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1967; 5 (Reel 28)
      - Finances, internal reports, 1967; 6 (Reel 28)
      - Releases, literature, 1967; 7 (Reel 28)
      - Miscellaneous material, 1967; 8 (Reel 28)
      - New contacts, 1967; 9 (Reel 28)
      - List of sponsors, 1967; 10 (Reel 28)
      - Fifth Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade Committee regarding Mobilization, 1967; 11 (Reel 28)
      - Student mobilization, 1967; 12 (Reel 28)
      - West Coast, 1967; 13 (Reel 28)
      - Publicity, 1967; 14 (Reel 28)
    - Genocide Petition, 15 (Reel 28)
    - Mobilization Program, 1967; 16 (Reel 28)
      March-May 1967
    - Meeting on Nonviolence, 1967; 17 (Reel 28)
      May 18, 1967.
    - Picketing at New York pier to protest Hiroshima, 1967; 18 (Reel 28)
      August 10, 1967.
    - Protest at the Pentagon, 1967; 19 (Reel 28)
      October 21, 1967.
  - Morgan, John (case), 20 (Reel 28)
  - Muste, A.J., 21 (Reel 28)
  - Birthday celebrations, 1958-1967; 22 (Reel 28)
    1958-1963, 1965, 1967
  - N (General), 23 (Reel 28)
  - National Coordinating Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 24 (Reel 28)
  - O (General), 25 (Reel 28)
  - P (General), 26 (Reel 28)
  - Peace Agitator, 27 (Reel 28)
  - Peace News, 28 (Reel 28)
  - Peace Research Institute, 29 (Reel 28)
  - Program on nonviolence, 30 (Reel 28)
  - Quaker Action Group, 31 (Reel 28)
  - R (General), 32 (Reel 28)
  - Radical contacts (unaffiliated), 33 (Reel 28)
  - Rapoport, Anatol (correspondence), 34 (Reel 28)
  - Russell, Bertrand (War Crimes Tribunal, International), 35 (Reel 28)
  - Russell, Bertrand (Peace Foundation), 36 (Reel 28)
  - S (General), 37 (Reel 28)
  - School of Conflict Management, 1 (Reel 29)
  - Seeger, Daniel (court case), 2 (Reel 29)
  - Self-immolation, 3 (Reel 29)
  - Sons and Daughters, 1967; 4 (Reel 29)
    film protesting Vietnam War
  - Soviet Peace Committee, 5 (Reel 29)
  - Speak Out at Pentagon, 1965; 6 (Reel 29)
    June 16, 1965.
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 7 (Reel 29)
  - Support in Action, 8 (Reel 29)
  - T (General), 9 (Reel 29)
  - TTP-AFSC Controversy, 10 (Reel 29)
  - Thomas, Norman, 11 (Reel 29)
  - New York Times correspondence, 12 (Reel 29)
  - Triple Revolution, 13 (Reel 29)
  - Triple Revolution Conference, 1964; 14 (Reel 29)
    October 1964.
  - U (General), 15 (Reel 29)
  - Box 50 - V (General), 16 (Reel 29)
  - Vietnam (correspondence), 17 (Reel 29)
  - Vietnam, 18 (Reel 29)
    - March on Washington to End the War in Vietnam, 1965; 19 (Reel 29)
      April 1965.
    - March on Washington for Peace in Vietnam, 1965; 20 (Reel 29)
      November 1965.
    - Proposed projects, 21 (Reel 29)
    - Protests, fasts (miscellaneous), 22 (Reel 29)
    - Vietnam Summer, 1967; 23 (Reel 29)
    - Vietnam reading material, 1964-1965; 1 (Reel 30)
    - Vietnam reading material, 1966-1967; 1 (Reel 31)
    - Vietnam clippings, 1965-1967, 1966-1967; 2 (Reel 31)
  - W (General), 3 (Reel 31)
  - War Crimes Tribunal, 4 (Reel 31)
    see Russell, Bertrand
  - "Who Has the Spiritual Atom Bomb?" by A.J. Muste (correspondence), 5 (Reel 31)
  - Women's Peace Team to North Vietnam, 6 (Reel 31)
  - World Council of Peace (Stockholm Meeting, etc.), 7 (Reel 31)
  - World Peace Brigade, 8 (Reel 31)
    see main body of correspondence, 1958-1963
  - X,Y,Z, 9 (Reel 31)
- Memo reports and articles, 10 (Reel 31)
- Material written by others and sent to Muste, 1 (Reel 32)
- Communist Party Convention, 1957; 2 (Reel 32)
- Nonviolence: Theory and Case Studies, 3 (Reel 32)
- Birthday, Christmas Greetings, 1963; 1 (Reel 33)
- Delhi-Peking March, 1963; 2 (Reel 33)
- Everyman III, 1962-1963; 3 (Reel 33)
- Soviet Peace Committee, 1962-1963; 4 (Reel 33)
- Africa Freedom Action Project, 1962-1963; 5 (Reel 33)
- CNVA, F.O.R., 1962-1964; 6 (Reel 33)
- Miscellaneous material, 1962-1963; 7 (Reel 33)
- A-M (General), 8 (Reel 33)
- N-Z (General), 1 (Reel 34)
- Hudson Institute, 1964-1966; 2 (Reel 34)
- Fort Hood Three, 1966-1967; 3 (Reel 34)
  October 1966-January 1967
- Scrapbook, 1 (Reel 35)
- Correspondence, 1938-1965; 1 (Reel 36)
  one letter each-1938, 1941, 1949, 1963, 1965
- Writings, 1939-1955; 2 (Reel 36)
  one each- 1939, circa 1940, 1955
- Obituaries, death notices, editorials, memorial articles, memorial services and tributes, 1967; 3 (Reel 36)
  February 11, 1967, and following
- Newspaper clippings, 4 (Reel 36)
  - Trip to North Vietnam, 1967; 5 (Reel 36)
    January 1967.
  - Reviews and notices of "The Essays of A.J. Muste," edited by Nat Hentoff, 1967; 6 (Reel 36)
    March-April 1967.
- Anti-war demonstrations, New York, 1966-1967; 7 (Reel 36)
- Biographical material, 8 (Reel 36)
- Miscellaneous writings by Muste, 1963-1965; 9 (Reel 36)
- Correspondence file in alphabetical order as kept by Muste, 1963-1964; 10 (Reel 36)
- General correspondence from various sources, 1961-1964; 11 (Reel 36)
- Miscellaneous, 12 (Reel 36)
- American European March, 1961; 13 (Reel 36)
- Amnesty for Smith Act Victims, 1954-1957; 1 (Reel 37)
- Bently Proposal, 1965; 2 (Reel 37)
- Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, 1964; 3 (Reel 37)
- Church Peace Mission, 1963; 4 (Reel 37)
- Clark, George, Visit, 1965; 5 (Reel 37)
- Committee for an April 17 March on Washington to End the War in Vietnam (no date), 6 (Reel 37)
- Committee for Nonviolent Action (CNVA), 1962-1964; 7 (Reel 37)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 8 (Reel 37)
  - International visits, 9 (Reel 37)
  - Soviet visit, 10 (Reel 37)
    - Miscellaneous and correspondence, 11 (Reel 37)
    - Schedule and meetings, 12 (Reel 37)
    - Publicity, 13 (Reel 37)
    - Correspondence with Soviets, 14 (Reel 37)
  - Quebec-Washington-Guantanamo Walk (Q-W-G), 1963-1964; 15 (Reel 37)
    - Albany, Macon, Griffin, 16 (Reel 37)
    - Correspondence with government officials, 17 (Reel 37)
    - General correspondence, 18 (Reel 37)
    - Supporting demonstrations, 19 (Reel 37)
    - Passports-general correspondence, 20 (Reel 37)
    - Passports-state Department, 21 (Reel 37)
    - Cuban Government, 22 (Reel 37)
    - Reports and internal correspondence, 23 (Reel 37)
    - Contributions and appeals, 24 (Reel 37)
- Engagements, 1963-1966; 1 (Reel 38)
- Fellowship of Reconciliation, New York, 1964-1966; 2 (Reel 38)
- Fort Hood Defense Committee, 1966; 3 (Reel 38)
  - Correspondence, 4 (Reel 38)
  - New York Times Ad and Petition, 5 (Reel 38)
  - Finances, 6 (Reel 38)
  - Sponsorship, 7 (Reel 38)
- International Conference of Non-aligned Organizations Working for Nuclear and General Disarmament, 1963; 8 (Reel 38)
  January 4-7, 1963.
- Liberation, 1963-1965; 9 (Reel 38)
- Nonviolent Education Fund, Bayard Rustin's Oslo trip, 1964; 10 (Reel 38)
- North American Regional Council Minutes, 1962-1964; 11 (Reel 38)
  - Literature, 12 (Reel 38)
  - Finances, 13 (Reel 38)
  - Lists, 14 (Reel 38)
  - Reports, 15 (Reel 38)
  - Newsletter: articles and clippings, 1 (Reel 39)
- European Regional Council, 2 (Reel 39)
- Asian Regional Council, 3 (Reel 39)
- Asian Regional Council, 4 (Reel 39)
- Scandinavian Section, 5 (Reel 39)
- London Regional Office, 6 (Reel 39)
- Africa Freedom Action Project, 7 (Reel 39)
- Individuals, 8 (Reel 39)
  - Deo, Shankarrao, 9 (Reel 39)
  - Dhadda, Siddharaj, 10 (Reel 39)
  - Lazar, Ed, 11 (Reel 39)
  - Nrayan, Jayaprakash, 12 (Reel 39)
  - Ram, Suresh, 13 (Reel 39)
  - Randle, Michael, 14 (Reel 39)
  - Scott, Michael, 15 (Reel 39)
  - Shugei, Bhikshu, 16 (Reel 39)
  - Sutherland, William, 17 (Reel 39)
  - Willoughby, George, 18 (Reel 39)
- Chinese contacts, 19 (Reel 39)
- Albert Bigelow meetings, 20 (Reel 39)
- Delhi-Peking Friendship March, 1962-1964; 21 (Reel 39)
  - General correspondence, 22 (Reel 39)
  - Minutes/reports, 23 (Reel 39)
  - Chinese Peace Committee, 24 (Reel 39)
  - Miscellaneous, 25 (Reel 39)